Guide to the Association of Gay and Lesbian Psychologists records, 1973-1992.
Association of Gay and Lesbian Psychologists records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Association of Gay and Lesbian Psychologists records, 1973-1992.
7592
Association of Gay and Lesbian Psychologists.
.5 cubic ft.
Correspondence, printed materials, publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Minutes, correspondence, financial records (1975-1986); an annotated copy of APA convention program (1973), and AGP newsletters.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Founded in 1973 as the Association of Gay Psychologists, it changed its name to the Association of Gay and Lesbian Psychologists in 1983. It is a nationwide professional organization composed of lesbian and gay psychologists who work together toward objectives including the elimination of "the conception of homosexuality as a clinical entity, and to encourage the reconceptualization of human sexuality in terms of its diversity and potentiality; to supply constructive alternatives within psychology to the traditional unscientific and unquestioned assumptions about homosexually-oriented persons, and to educate persons in the mental health fields...about the psychological, social, political, economic, and religious oppression of gay men and lesbians."
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Minutes, correspondence, financial records (1975-1986); an annotated copy of APA convention program (1973), and AGP newsletters.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Association of Gay and Lesbian Psychologists.; Association of Gay Psychologists.
Subjects:
Gay men.; Lesbians.; Psychology -- Study and teaching.; Psychology -- Societies, etc.; Psychologists.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Collecting Program: Human Sexuality Collection.
Related Collection: Society for the Psychological Study of Lesbian and Gay Issues records, #7580.
CONTAINER LIST
- APA 81st Annual Convention: Montreal, August 25-31, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- AGP Newsletters, 1973-1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- ALGP Newsletters, 1983-1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- ALGP Newsletters, 1986-1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- ALGP Archive, 1973-1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- ALGP Newsletters, 1981-1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Journal of Lesbian and Gay Psychology, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- AGP 1981-1984, 1981-1984 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- ALGP 1984, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- ALGP 1985, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- ALGP 1986, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- ALGP 1987, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- ALGP 1988, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- NALGP Transition 1993-1994, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- NALGP Membership/Resource List, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Job Descriptions (Box 2, Folder 10)